~ Clara! ~ 'Shut up.'
Is that how we communicate now?
Shut up, shut up, shut up.
I need to talk to you.
Well, I'll be there in a
couple of minutes, so...
~ No, not while you're in the room.
~ Oh, stupid me. The very idea!
~ Shut up! ~ 'OK.' ~ Stay shut up.
OK.
Things to say. Not all of them good.
Oh, wouldn't it be better
if I was actually there?
Danny, everything is better
when you're here, but maybe...
Maybe not this.
OK.
Um...
OK, before all of that.
Before all of the stuff
that I did wrong...
~ I love you. ~ I love you.
'No, not like that.
Not like it's automatic.'
Not like it's how you end
the phone call,
~ the sign off, the pat on the back.
~ Clara...
Danny, I'll never say those words
again. Not to anybody else, ever.
Those words, from me, are yours now.
So, erm...
That's a thing.
OK, Danny?
Um, there's more
but that's kind of the headline.
OK, Danny, please speak to me,
This is, this is killing me.
Danny, I love you.
And you are the last person who's
ever going to hear me say that.
'Hello?
'Hello, is someone there?'
Hello? Er, yeah, who's this?
'I just picked up the phone,
I'm sorry. I found it.
Oh. Um, OK. Er...
Can you please just put me
back on the phone to Danny?
I was talking to Danny.
'I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.'
OK, what are you sorry about?
Could you please just pass
the phone back to...?
'He was crossing the road.
'I found the phone,
it must have just got thrown...
'The car, it just came out
of nowhere.'
I'm so sorry.
'By now, I'm sure you've heard
the rumours
'and it is with great sadness that
I must confirm them to be true.
'I have gathered you all here
today to say that Mr Pink,
'that Danny Pink has
sadly passed away.
'I'm sure you'll all join me
in wishing his family and friends
'our sincerest condolences.
'Mr Pink was an inspiration
to all of those who knew him.
'A soldier, a teacher, a friend.
'It was no secret that he had a
close relationship with Miss Oswald.
'And our thoughts and prayers
are with her too.'
Hello, love. You all right?
Of course you're not.
Sorry. Of course
you're not all right.
You know what you should do?
You should cry. Let go.
Of what?
It's a terrible thing. Just a
terrible, terrible thing.
It wasn't terrible.
Clara?
It was boring.
Boring?
It was ordinary.
People just kept walking with
their iPods and their shopping bags.
He was alive, then he was dead
and it was nothing.
Like stepping off a bus.
He deserved better. And so did you.
I don't deserve anything.
Nobody deserves anything.
But I am owed better.
I am owed.
Who owes you?
'Clara!
'Clara?'
Hey!
Sorry, I was busy. What's happening?
Oh, nothing. You know, same old,
same old.
Well, you're only human.
'So what I can do for you, Clara?'
Clara?
~ Start her up! ~ Where are we going?
~ Away.
~ From? ~ Just away.
Well, normally you say work or
kids or dishes or dullness.
So what's happened?
~ A volcano. ~ I'm sorry?
I've never seen an active
volcano, do you know one?
What's so great about
seeing a volcano?
~ It's just a sort of leaky mountain.
~ I've never seen lava.
It's rubbish.
Prove it.
It's on your neck.
Do you still have those
sleep patch things?
~ You can't have one.
~ I'm having trouble sleeping.
~ You still can't have one.
~ Can I have one?
No, you can't have one.
So, volcano.
What's so good about lava?
You told me once what it would
take to destroy a TARDIS key.
That's what's so good about lava.
All seven. From all of
your hiding places.
Clara, what are you doing?
Don't. Be very, very careful with
that. Those are very, very...
Do I have your attention?
~ Yes. ~ Good.
No. Not good, Clara.
Danny Pink.
Yeah?
Is dead.
And?
~ Seriously? ~ And?
And fix it.
Change it.
Change what happened, save him.
Bring him back.
No.
Five left.
Every time you say no to me, I will
throw another key down there.
Do we understand each other?
Well, I understand you,
let's not get carried away.
Time can be rewritten.
With precision.
With great care.
And not today.
But you know that of course
otherwise you wouldn't
be threatening me.
Did you just say no?
If I...
change the events
that brought you here,
you will never come here and
ask me to change those events.
Paradox loop.
The timeline disintegrates.
Your timeline. And yes!
~ Yes? ~ Yes...
.. I did just say no.
Throw away the key.
I have seen you change time, I have
seen you break any rule you want.
I know when I can, I know
when I can't. Throw the key.
I know what you're doing.
You're trying to take control.
~ I am in control. Throw away the key,
do as you are told. ~ No!
Well, either you do as you're told
or stop threatening me.
There really isn't
a third option here.
Do you know what, Doctor?
When it comes to taking control,
you really are out of your depth.
One last chance.
And I don't care about the rules,
I don't give a damn about paradoxes.
Save Danny, bring him back
or I swear...
.. you will never step inside
your TARDIS again.
~ No. ~ Do as you are told.
~ No. ~ Say it again so I know
you mean it. ~ No!
~ I'm not kidding, Doctor...
~ Neither am I. ~ .. I will do it!
Clara, my Clara,
I don't think you will!
Oh, I'd say I'm sorry
but I'd do it again.
I'd do it again.
Well, what are you doing?
Why are you just standing there?
Do you understand
what I have just done?
~ Look in your hand.
~ There's nothing in my hand.
~ Clara, look in your hand. ~ The keys,
they're gone. They're down there.
~ Clara, look in your hand.
~ There's nothing in my hand.
Yes, yes, yes, there is, look.
Did you seriously think that
that was going to work on me?
They're not sleep patches.
They induce a dream state.
Makes you very suggestible.
I allowed the whole scenario
to play out just as you planned.
I was curious about how far
you would go.
~ Well, now you know.
~ Yeah...
now I know.
I love him.
Yes, you're quite the mess
of chemicals, aren't you?
So, what now?
What do we do now? You and me,
what happens now?
Doctor?
Go to hell.
Fair enough.
Absolutely fair enough.
Clara?
You asked me what we're going to do.
I told you.
We're going to hell.
Or wherever it is people go
when they die. If there is anywhere.
Wherever it is, we're going to go
there and we're going to find Danny.
And if it is in any way possible,
we're going to bring him home.
Almost every culture in the universe
has some concept of an afterlife.
I always meant to have a look
around, see if I could find one.
~ You're going to help me?
~ Well, why wouldn't I help you?
~ Cos of what I just did. I just...
~ You betrayed me.
Betrayed my trust,
you betrayed our friendship,
you betrayed everything that I've
ever stood for. You let me down!
Then why are you helping me?
Why?
Do you think I care for you
so little that betraying me
would make a difference?
Stop it with the eyes.
Don't do that with the eyes.
How do you do that anyway?
It's like they inflate!
Cut out the whining
while you're at it.
We've got work to do. This is it,
Clara, one of those moments.
~ What moments? ~ The darkest day.
The blackest hour.
Chin up, shoulders back.
Let's see what we're made of,
you and I.
Switching off the safeguards,
turning off the nav-com.
Remember, we did this before.
We plugged you into the
TARDIS telepathic interface.
We ended up all over
Danny's timestream.
Because you and he are linked,
strongly linked.
Your timestreams are intertwined.
So if he's anywhere at all, that
link will hold. Give me your hands.
~ Doctor... ~ We're in a hurry.
I don't deserve a friend like you.
Clara, I'm terribly sorry but
I'm exactly what you deserve.
Think about Danny. Think about
the man you lost.
Let it hurt. Let it burn.
But don't bleat.
Don't ask, why him? Why me? Forget
all that. Ask one question.
Just one.
Ask, where is Danny Pink now?
Where is he now?
Well...
the TARDIS thinks he's somewhere.
Has anyone offered you a coffee?
Um...
Well, no.
Could we have some coffee
along here, please?
The good kind. We've got a new one.
Five minutes, tops. Best to wait
for the good coffee.
~ Where am I? ~ Sometimes it's
just the instant, oh...
Where am I?
Well, big question.
Try to take that one slowly.
We have been trying
to contact family members,
but really there is so much admin...
I wasn't here, I was...
Yeah. That last thing
that happened to you,
that really happened, I'm afraid.
But that's life.
Well, not life, I suppose, but...
There are some forms to fill in.
Might help you relax.
Well, they won't, but we do
need them filled in.
Right, important thing.
Need to know.
Are you being cremated?
Sorry, it's a fairly
urgent question.
I don't know. I've never really
thought of that.
I'm going to put you down
as a yes,
that's pretty much
the default these days.
~ If people only knew...
~ Only knew what?
We've got a burner in number 12.
~ Tell them to prep, please.
~ Burner?
Yeah, it's fine, we'll come to that.
But I don't understand where I am.
Oh, look at that.
You can see my house from here.
Yeah, sorry, probably not helping.
Where am I?
Um...
You sort of know, don't you?
Most people kind of know, it's just
hard to get traction on the concept.
Where am I?
OK. You're dead.
And this is what's next.
~ I'm not dead. How can I be dead?
~ Our sincere condolences.
~ I'm standing right here.
~ Yes, you are.
Welcome to the Underworld.
Otherwise known as the Nethersphere,
or the Promised Land.
It's where you go when you die.
Would you like to breathe
into a bag?
Where are we?
Nav-com's offline. We'll have
to do this old school.
But this is where Danny is?
Almost certainly not. It's where
there's a connection with Danny.
According to the TARDIS, this is
where it's most likely that
your timeline will re-intersect
with his. And that won't do.
~ What won't? ~ You won't, look at you.
I need sceptical, clever, critical.
I don't need mopey.
It put years on your face.
And what if people see us together?
~ It looks like you've been melted.
~ Are you forgetting why we're here?
We're here to get your boyfriend
back from the dead,
so buck up and
give me some attitude.
Fish tanks?
In a mausoleum?
~ What does that mean? ~ It means those
are definitely not fish tanks.
~ Why? ~ I don't know.
OK, I'm assuming they didn't
actually drown in there.
No.
They were placed, after death.
These are tombs.
Water tombs, some sort of
fluid, anyway.
~ With chairs? ~ With chairs, yes.
Extra comfort for the deceased,
it pays to die rich.
Oh, God.
Am I going to find Danny now? Is
that why the TARDIS brought us here?
~ I don't want to see him like that.
~ Good point.
Tombs with windows. Who wants to
watch their loved ones rot?
Why would anyone go to
so much trouble...
just to keep watch on the dead?
'3W.
'Death is not an end.
'But we can we help with that.
'Ever since 3W encountered the truth
about the death experience,
'we have been working hard to find
a better life for the deceased.
'At 3W, afterlife means aftercare.'
OK. Bit strange?
Very.
Why have the scrolling and a voice?
Is it difficult?
Is what difficult?
Reading all those words
back to front.
Come on. We've come a long way.
Hello. I hope you're well.
How may I assist you with your death?
Well, there is, er,
no immediate hurry.
We're just, er...
We're just... Er...
~ Browsing. ~ Yeah, yeah, browsing.
Please, take all the time you need.
At 3W, you always have
the rest of your life.
~ Oh, good. That's good to know,
Clara, isn't it? ~ Yeah. Great.
~ Exactly what is 3W? ~ Apologies.
Clearly you have not received the
official 3W greetings package.
Well, you know, it's just
an unexpected...
Welcome to the 3W Institute.
Clara...
is it over now?
I think it's over, yeah.
You also have not received
the official welcome package.
Oh, I'm good. Thanks, no worries.
Who are you?
~ I am Missy. ~ Missy?
Mobile Intelligent Systems Interface.
I am a multi-function,
interactive welcome-droid.
Helping you to help me to help you.
You're very...
~ realistic. ~ Tongues? ~ Shut up.
I am fully programmed with
social interaction norms
appropriate to a range of visitors.
Please indicate if you'd like me
to adjust my intimacy setting.
Oh, yes, please. Please do that,
do that now right now.
Maybe just a tad, yeah.
I need to speak to
whoever's in charge here.
I am in charge.
Well, who's in charge of you?
I'm in charge of me.
Well, who repairs you?
Who maintains you?
I am programmed for self-repair.
I am maintained by my heart.
Is everything in order?
Who maintains your heart?
My heart is maintained
by the Doctor.
Doctor who?
Dr Chang!
Who's there?
Hello?
Hello.
You can probably take your
hand down now, Doctor.
So. Hey.
Condolences!
~ Condolences? ~ It's a mausoleum.
It's our hello.
Is there a particular dead person
you want to talk to?
Yes.
Yes, there is.
This way then.
~ Are you OK? ~ No.
Good. There would be something
very wrong if you were.
Bit of fresh air. Do you good.
~ Why's it so cold here? ~ And the Wi-Fi
is better out here. Don't know why.
~ Wi-Fi? ~ Yeah, still a bit spotty,
but basically...
You have Wi-Fi here?
You... You have iPads
in the afterlife?
IPads? We have Steve Jobs!
Listen, another big question
for you.
Have you ever killed anybody?
This is surreal.
Imagine embryos had telephones.
~ That's really not helping.
~ Go with me. Go with me.
Imagine babies in wombs could talk
to other babies in other wombs.
What would they say?
What would they think life was like
if they could talk among themselves?
I really have no idea.
They'd think that life was
nine months long.
Then, boom, trap door opens,
out you fall, gone for ever.
Never hear from those guys again.
Nothing at the end of the cord.
OK.
This isn't really an afterlife.
It's just more life
than you were expecting.
Why did you ask me
if I'd killed anyone?
Before you were a teacher,
you spent some time as a soldier.
Yeah, so?
Any regrets? Bad memories?
Is that any of your business?
Yes.
Get to cover, now!
Sorry if I triggered something then.
Memory flashes can be very impactful
in the early stages.
Why?
Why what?
'Why is it any of your business?'
We've had a request to meet you.
Any idea who that would be from?
It's been given a priority,
which usually means...
Means what?
Well, anyway, we've arranged
a meet-up.
When?
Come in.
'Danny, repeat, is
the building secure?'
So, I guess you remember him, yeah?
'Danny? Danny?'
Come in, come in.
~ Going to need to take
a reading off you. ~ A reading?
~ Won't hurt. ~ What won't?
How does the body
keep its integrity?
Why isn't it just a bunch
of bones floating about?
Each body is encased in
a support exoskeleton.
'An invisible exoskeleton?'
'It's only invisible in the water.
There's a specially engineered
'refraction index in the fluid
so we can see the tank resident
'unimpeded by the
support mechanisms.'
'So each skeleton is
inside something?'
~ Are you serious? X-ray water?
~ It's so cool.
Look at this.
We call it dark water.
Only organic matter
can be seen through it.
I keep saying they should use
this stuff in swimming pools.
~ Why? ~ Think about it.
I am thinking about it. Why?
Doesn't matter.
3W, what kind of name is that?
What does it mean?
Well, you know, don't you?
You're here on business or
they wouldn't have let you in.
Sorry. Should have checked.
Who are you?
I thought that you would never ask.
Sort out your security protocols,
they're a disgrace.
Another government inspection?
So soon?
Why is there all this swearing?
Oh, I've got a lot of
internalised anger.
What does 3W stand for?
Well, the three words.
What three words?
~ Seriously? You don't know? ~ Never mind
what we know and what we don't know,
just answer our question.
Because people who don't know,
when they hear about this,
~ they can freak out.
~ We're not going to freak out.
If you've had a recent loss,
this might be...
This will be disturbing.
~ She'll be fine. ~ Speak for me again,
I'll detach something from you.
I'll be fine.
You know how people are scared
of dying? Like, everybody.
Of course, it's the most fundamental
fear in the universe.
They'd be a lot more scared if they
knew what it was really like.
So...
You OK?
I'm sorry.
I just...
Hey, hey... Hey, listen.
Listen...
Hey!
Probably best not, eh?
Doesn't speak much.
Why would he want to see me?
What the hell is that?
Sounds like somebody
left their body to science.
OK. Um...
It's probably time to explain
why you're always feeling cold...
White noise off the telly.
We've all heard it.
A few years ago, Dr Skarosa,
our founder,
did something unexpected.
He played that noise through
a translation matrix
of his own devising.
This is a recording of what he heard.
~ OK. People. Voices. ~ So what?
Over time, Dr Skarosa
became convinced
these were the voices of
the recently departed.
He believed it was a telepathic
communication from the dead.
Why?
Was he an idiot?
He was able to isolate some of the
voices, hear what they were saying.
So... an idiot then.
Shut up, Doctor.
What I'm about to play you
will change your life
and not for the better. These are the
three words which caused Dr Skarosa
to set up institutes, like this one,
all over the world
to protect the dead.
If you'd rather not hear these
words, there's still time...
Can you just hurry up, please?
Or I'll hit you with my shoe.
'Don't cremate me.
Don't cremate me!'
There is one simple, horrible
possibility that has never occurred
to anyone throughout human history.
'Don't cremate me.
Don't cremate me!'
Don't say it.
The dead remain conscious.
The dead are fully aware of
everything that is happening to them.
So your mind is here, your soul,
whatever you want to call it
and you're in your new body
in your new world.
But you're still connected to
your old body in the old world.
You're still going
to feel what it feels.
That's why I'm cold.
They're keeping you
in a cold place, yeah.
You did say you were being cremated?
Sorry, I'll get this.
~ Sorry. Sorry, are you telling me...?
~ Wow! Oh, that's rare.
This never happens.
~ Wow, what now? What never happens?
~ You've got a call.
~ A call? ~ From the other side. ~ Meaning?
Do you know somebody called
Clara Oswald?
Fakery. All of it.
It's a con, it's a racket!
I promise you this is not a con.
What's that beeping?
'Never mind about beeping,
who cares about beeping?
'The dead are dead!
'They're not talking to you
out of your television sets.
'They're just gone and all these
poor souls down there in these tanks
'I'm sorry, but they're just dead
and they're not coming back.'
'Clara? Clara?
'Clara, are you there?'
Danny!
I can hear you. Is that you?
Oh, please, say it's you.
That's her, that's Clara!
Yeah, you're really lucky,
it hardly ever happens.
Where did she go?
Ah.
Hm. Er...
Just lost the signal, but I can
track it back, I'm pretty sure...
I don't understand.
What is happening?
We've been scanning you
telepathically since you came in.
You said you wanted to speak
to someone who'd passed.
And we've found you a match
in the Nethersphere.
This isn't possible.
The dead don't come back.
~ Come on, get her back. ~ Da-da-da!
I'm trying.
It was him, it was his voice.
If they scanned you telepathically,
they could've lifted a voice print,
it could still be a fake.
Getting him back - very nearly!
Clara, can you hear me?
Yes, Danny, I can hear you.
Can you hear me?
Yeah, yeah, I can hear you.
Clara! Oh, God.
~ Clara... ~ What do I do?
~ Who are you talking to? ~ Hang on
just a moment. ~ Question him.
Ask him questions only he'd know
the answer to. Be sure.
~ You - with me. ~ Where are you going?
~ I've got to check out those tanks.
There's something that I'm missing.
'Clara?'
Sceptical and critical, remember?
Be strong - even if it
breaks your heart.
Connection's stabilised,
it should be OK.
Who would harvest dead bodies?
I feel like I'm missing
something obvious.
Danny?
Yeah, I'm here.
Danny, I'm so sorry but I'm going
to have to ask you some questions.
Questions? I swear on
anything it's me!
Humankind, bring out your dead.
Oh, my God!
The tanks...
The tanks are activating!
~ They're not supposed to do that. ~ And
all your dead people are standing.
~ Don't you think you skipped
the headline? ~ Now, now, children.
Naughty, naughty!
Dr Chang...
your welcome droid
has developed a fault.
That's not a droid. That's my boss.
You know I might have been guilty
of a just teensy, little fibette.
Dr Chang...
I really liked working with you.
~ I've enjoyed every day of it.
~ I'm sorry?
You know, I've even got a little
photograph of you looking so sweet.
I'm always going to keep it. Always!
~ Are you going to kill me?
~ Now, come on.
Let's not dwell on horrid things.
This is going to be
our last conversation
and I'm the one who's going
to have to live with that.
Please don't kill me.
Say something nice.
Please, please. I...
I don't want to die.
You're going to kill me, aren't you?
~ Say something nice. ~ Please!
Dr Chang, I've got all day
and I'm not going to kill you
until you say something nice.
It has been an absolute pleasure
working with you and I truly believe
that you'll never be able to
find it in your heart to murder me.
Now, I'll be with you in a moment.
Just...
feeling a bit emotional
at the moment.
Cybermen!
It's me. I... I swear on anything
it's me.
'The very first restaurant
you took me to - that first date.
~ 'What was it called?'
~ Clara, it's me.
Then what was the name
of the restaurant?
What was it?
I can't remember!
They're Cybermen, all of them,
we've got to stop them getting out.
Now who's missing the headline?
The Nethersphere.
You know it's ever so funny,
the people that live inside that
think they've gone to heaven.
'My birthday. When is it?'
November 23rd. That's right,
isn't it? I got that one right.
'It's pretty basic information.
'Anyone could know that.
Say something only you could say.'
Tell me something only
Danny would know.
That's a matrix data-slice.
A Gallifreyan hard drive.
Time Lord technology.
Imagine you could upload
dying minds to that.
Edit them. Rearrange them.
Get rid of all those
boring emotions.
Ready to be re-downloaded.
Meanwhile, you upgrade the bodies.
Upload the mind, upgrade the body.
Cybermen from cyberspace.
Now, why has no-one ever thought
of that before?
How did you get hold of
Time Lord technology?
Who are you?
You know who I am.
I told you.
You felt it.
Surely you did.
Two hearts.
And both of them yours.
You're a Time Lord.
Time Lady, please,
I'm old-fashioned.
Which Time Lady?
The one you abandoned, Doctor.
The one you left for dead.
Didn't you ever think
I'd find my way back?
Clara! Clara! Clara!
I've got to get Clara!
Oh, Clara, Clara, Clara!
You know I should shoot you
in a jealous rage.
Now, wouldn't that be sexy?
~ I've turned the lift off, though.
~ I presume you have stairs.
Well, I'm not a Dalek.
Oh, dear, Doctor.
Didn't you realise where you were?
~ 'I love you.' ~ No.
No, no, no. I'm sorry, but no.
Anybody could say that.
Anybody would know to say that. Say
something only you could tell me.
Prove to me you are really Danny.
~ How? ~ 'I love you means nothing
right now.'
Not until I know who's talking.
Say something only Danny could say.
Clara...
'Danny...
'.. if that is you...'
wherever you are, whatever it takes,
'I will be with you again, I swear.'
No, you won't.
You are not coming here.
'Nothing will stop me,
nothing in the world,'
~ as soon as I know it's you.
~ 'There is only one way to come here'
~ and you are not doing that.
~ 'I'll do anything, Danny, anything.'
Just... say something
only you could say.
Clara, you have your life.
You have your whole life to live.
You have to stay there.
No. I have to be with Danny Pink.
I love you.
Stop saying that! Don't say that.
If you say that again, I swear
I will switch this thing off.
Clara...
'Yes?'
I love you.
These emotions,
they're terribly difficult.
But, you know, we've got a thing
for that.
We can help with all
these difficult feelings.
Just press this.
I'll leave you to make a decision.
Doctor!
Get away from here!
All of you, run!
Go! Go! Get away from here!
Run away!
Run, run! Get away from here
all of you, now!
I'm sorry, everyone, another ranting
Scotsman in the street.
~ I had no idea there was a match on.
~ Get away, go!
Stop shouting, love. Stop making
a fuss, it's too late.
All the graves of planet Earth
are about to give birth.
You know the key strategic
weakness of the human race?
The dead outnumber the living.
Who are you?
Oh, you know who I am.
I'm Missy.
Who's Missy?
Please, try to keep up.
Short for Mistress.
Well...
.. I couldn't very well
keep calling myself...
the Master, now could I?
www.tvsubtitles.net